《异形魔怪》
早安 贝斯特先生 起床时间到了
Good morning, Mr. Basset. This is your wake-up call.
快快清醒吧
Please move your ass.
牛群狂奔
Stampede!
牛群狂奔 厄尔 快逃 快逃
Stampede, Earl! Get out of the way!
你这混蛋
You dumb shit.
我还真遇过牛群狂奔
I was in a stampede once.
三百头牛拼命地奔跑
300 head going hell-bent for the horizon.
厄尔 到底怎样才叫牛群狂奔？
Exactly how many cows are required for a stampede, Earl?
三头牛还是更多头牛？有最低速限吗？
I mean, is it like three or more? Is there a minimum speed?
真希望牛群踢烂你屁股
I wish a stampede up your ass.
早餐呢？
No breakfast?
昨天是我煮的 我们吃了香肠和豆子
I did it yesterday. It was bologna and beans.
才不是 昨天吃蛋
No. It was eggs.
我煮的荷包蛋
I did eggs over easy
你煮个头 明明就是香肠和豆子 今天换你煮了
The hell you did. Bologna and beans. It's your turn.
等我到了你这把年纪 也会不记得吃过什么
I guess when I'm your age…I'll forget what I eat, too.
哦 可恶
Goddamn it!
我问你 这工作是给聪明人做的吗？
I ask you, is this a job for intelligent men?
找个聪明人来 我就问他
Show me one. I'll ask him.
我意思是 若真的想赚钱 就不该再做临时工
If we were serious about money, we'd quit being hired hands.
是杂工 厄尔 我们是杂工
Handymen, Earl. We are handymen.
对 我们不该做这种工作 而是找份真正的工作
We should quit this job…and find ourselves some real employment.
你想放弃遣份自由吗？
Are you going to give up all this personal freedom?
我不知道
I don't know.
上快速道路了
Freeway!
今天要做什么？
What's on the agenda for today?
- 收垃圾 - 哦 老天 又到了吗？
- It's garbage day. - Man! Already?
纳斯特付我们多少钱？
What's Nestor paying us?
50元 比我们手头上的钱多47元
$50. And that's $47 more than we got.
柏特和海瑟比较近
Burt and Heather's place is closer.
今天先帮他们做 明天再收垃圾
Let's do their linoleum today and the garbage tomorrow.
纳斯特明天不在家
Nestor's not home tomorrow.
今天不去 就拿不到钱
We don't dig today, we're not paid.
去你的 瓦蓝提 你做事从不事先计划
Damn it, Valentine, you never plan ahead.
也不放眼未来
You never take the long view.
今天是星期一 我已经在为星期三做打算
Here it is Monday and I'm already thinking of Wednesday.
今天是星期一 对吧？
It is Monday, right?
嘿 那是谁啊？
Who the hell's that?
不会是那个什么研究生吧？
That's not the grad student?
- 不是 他毕业了 一定是新来的 - 新来的？
- No. He graduated. Must be the new one. - The new one?
应该是个女生
That's supposed to be a girl.
有着金色长发
You will have long, blonde hair…
绿色大眼睛 世界级大胸部
big green eyes, world-class breasts…
翘翘的屁股 修长的美腿
ass that won't quit and legs that go all the way up!
嗨 我是兰达蕾贝克 这学期来这里做研究
Hi! I'm Rhonda LeBeck. I'm up here for the semester.
- 是哦 研究地理学 - 是地质学
- Yeah, geography. - Geology.
事实上是地震学 研究地震
Well, actually seismology. Earthquakes.
你们俩一定是厄尔和小瓦
You two must be Val and Earl.
- 我听说了很多你们的事 - 我们什么都不承认哦
- I've heard all about you. - We deny everything.
嘿 听着 我想请教一下
I've got a question for you.
你们知不知道有人在附近钻孔
Do you know if anybody's doing any drilling or blasting…
或爆破之类吗？
or anything like that?
这附近吗？没有
Around here? No, ma'am.
我正在监视地震仪
I'm supposed to monitor the seismographs.
地震仪能测量震动
You know, they measure vibrations.
来自地面的震动
Vibrations in the ground.
对
Yeah.
我一直收到一些很奇怪的读数
I've been getting some really strange readings.
三年前学校把这些机器放在这里
The school's had the machines here,
我们从没测到过像这样的记录
and we've never recorded anything like this.
我们会问问看是否有人听说过
We'll ask around. See if anyone's heard anything.
谢谢
Thanks.
希望机器没故障 否则我整学期都泡汤了
God, I hope they're not broken. I might have to bag the whole semester.
总之 很抱歉打扰了
Anyway, sorry to bother you.
没关系
No problem.
真高兴见到你 希望你能把一切理出头绪来
Nice meeting you. Hope you get it all sorted out.
如果你想的话 我们可以帮她
If you wanted, we could take a look at those…
检查地震仪
seismographs for her if you want.
我们对地震仪了解多少？
What the hell do we know about seismographs?
一点也不了解
Nothing.
这可能是接近她最好的方法
It might be a slick way to get to know her.
为什么？
Why?
他妈的 小瓦
Damn it, Valentine.
除非从头到脚都合乎你的标准 否则你根本不瞧一眼
You don't go for any gal unless she fits your list, top to bottom.
- 当然 - 对 你比我屁股还蠢
- Well sure! - It's dumber than my hind end.
就像芭比琳谭丝特
I mean, like that…Bobby Lynn Dexter.
是谭米琳芭丝特
Tammy Lynn Baxter.
有什么差 她们都一样麻烦
It don't matter. They're all the same. Dead weight.
「哦 我指甲断了」
"Oh, I broke a nail!"
看了都起鸡皮疙瘩
Makes my skin crawl.
我是这环境下的受害者
I'm a victim of circumstance.
我以为你在说你老二
I thought you call it your pecker.
（完美市）
（张华特杂货店）
嘿 大饼脸
Pizza-face!
马文？
Melvin.
马文 敢碰那辆卡车 就死定了
Melvin You touch that truck and die.
哦 老天 吓死我了
Man, I'm really shaking.
谢了 华特
Thanks, Walter.
这些是中空子弹 但不是海卓沙克中空子弹
These are hollow points, but not hydro-shock hollow points.
抱歉 我想子弹就是子弹
Bullets are bullets.
嗨 各位 近来如何？
Hi, guys. What's doing?
我们遇到新来的研究生兰娜
We ran into that new college student, that Rona.
是兰达 她的机器出了点
Rhonda. She's having trouble with her…
问题
things.
最后那些大学生 会在这里发现石油或铀
Those college kids turn up oil or uranium or something out there…
联邦官员就会出现在门口
next thing the Feds will be at our door.
说 「抱歉 请搬家 这里归政府所有」
"Sorry. Time to move. Eminent domain."
亲爱的 别激动
Down, honey. Down.
对 柏特 你这么杞人忧天
Yeah, Burt. The way you worry…
第三次世界大战都还没打 就先得心脏病
you'll get a heart attack before you get a chance to survive World War III.
等着瞧吧
We'll see.
嘿 你们听 轴承快坏了
Guys, listen. Bearing going out.
- 是不是？ - 可能吧
- What do you think? - Could be.
待会儿再帮你看看 我们还有别的活要赶
Later, Chang. We got a schedule to keep.
没错 我们凡事都先规划
Yeah. See, we plan ahead.
所以现在什么事都不做 厄尔这么跟我说的
That way we don't do anything right now. Earl explained it to me.
（密西根大学设备）
来杯鸡尾酒？
Cocktail?
好
You bet.
我告诉你
I'll tell you.
没有人比我们更会处理垃圾
Nobody handles garbage better than we do.
没错
Yep.
拜托 厄尔 这工作太低贱了
Come on, Earl. This is low.
我们得把眼光放高点
We have got to set our sights a little bit higher.
（张氏出租公司 化粪池抽水机）
嘿 马文 你怎么不帮帮忙 多半是你拉的屎尿
Melvin, why don't you give us a hand? Most of this shit is yours anyway.
听着 去店里帮我买六罐啤酒 我付钱
Listen, run to the store and pick me up a six-pack. I'll pay for it.
小于 未成年不能喝啤酒
Son, beer is for adults.
就是没有计划 我们才会一直做这种工作
Not having a plan is what keeps us doing jobs like this.
正因为这种工作 才让我们永远落人之后
Just doing jobs like this is you dragging your feet.
你竟敢公然地站在那里对我说
Are you going to stand there and tell me
是我让咱们滞留在完美市？
I'm the reason we're still in Perfection?
你知道我差点就离开这里了吗？
You know how close I am to leaving this place right now?
少胡扯了 哪有差点？
I'll call that little bluff. How close?
- 可恶 - 混帐
- Shit! - Goddamn!
老天 真该死
Jesus Christ! Goddamn!
别忘了带电视机
Don't forget the TV.
- 你带吸尘器干嘛？ - 我喜欢吸尘器
- Why you bringing the vacuum cleaner? - I like this vacuum.
- 你用不上的 - 至少零件会用得上
- You never use it. - It's good for parts.
而且你有想过吗？我们可能会请个女佣
Besides, maybe we'll hire a maid. You think about that?
上车吧
Get in the truck.
（厄尔贝斯特与小瓦麦基的家）
你们两个
Guys!
嘿 你们两个 等等
Hey, guys, wait!
嗨
Hi.
抱歉 南茜 我们不再运送木柴了
Sorry, Nancy. We're not delivering firewood anymore.
- 我们要去毕斯比定居 - 哦 是哦
- We're heading for Bixby permanent. - Sure.
哦 天啊 你是说真的
Oh, my God. You really are!
嘿 敏蒂 跳第几下了？
Mindy, what's the count?
六百四十下
640.
听着 我不需要木柴
I don't need firewood.
我接到大订单 必须建造新窑烧陶
I have this big order to fill and have to build my pottery kiln.
拜托 这工作至少能做一个月
Come on, it'll be at least a month's work.
我提供午餐
I'll throw in lunches.
还有啤酒
And beer.
真不敢相信 我们对免费啤酒说不
I can't believe we said no to free beer.
我们办到了 面对诱惑却不动摇
We did it! We faced temptation and did not bend!
真他妈的 感谢上帝
Goddamn! Praise the Lord!
现在没有任何东西 能阻止我们前往毕斯比
Now there's nothing, and I mean nothing, between us and Bixby.
- 没错 - 没错
- Yeah! - Yeah!
嘿 看看那家伙
Look at that guy!
和电有关的工作 我绝不做
That's one job I'd never do. Working around electricity.
等一下
Hold up.
那是艾格迪姆斯
That's Edgar Deems.
拜托
Come on.
他只穿那件夹克
He only wears that one damn jacket.
我敢说是他没错
That's him, I'm telling you.
老天 他这次肯定喝醉了
He sure must've been drunk this time.
艾格 快给我下来
Get your butt down from there!
可恶
Shit.
我们不能把他留在上面
We can't leave him up there.
真是谢了 艾格
Thank you, Edgar.
你欠我一次 你这老酒鬼
You owe me on this one, you damned old boozehound.
总有一天 你得被送去戒酒
One of these days, you'll have to get your ass on a wagon and stay there.
老天 当我闲着没事做
It's not like I don't have better things to do
只好爬电塔拉你下来啊
than climb towers and drag your hairy ass down.
我的天啊
Jesus!
医生 是心脏病发作吗？
Was it a heart attack, doctor?
不是
No.
他是脱水而死的 口渴死的
He died of dehydration. Thirst.
一点也没道理 要渴死也得花好几天 不是吗？
That doesn't make any sense. That takes a couple of days, doesn't it?
可能要三或四天吧
Maybe even three or four.
你意思是他坐在那里三或四天？
You mean he sat up there three or four days?
坐在那里直到渴死？
He sat up there and just died of thirst?
你觉得他比我们更恨完美市吗？
You reckon he hated Perfection more than us?
你觉得他想自杀吗？
Do you suppose he wanted to kill himself?
一定有人追他 他才不下来
Somebody must've chased him up there.
你是说有人不怕来福枪？
You mean someone that ain't scared of a Winchester rifle?
然后呢？
Then what'd they do?
在下面扎营 等他渴死？
Camp out and wait for him to die?
怎么回事？
What the hell?
搞什么？
What the shit?
嘿 弗瑞德
Fred!
你在哪里 老弗？
Hey, there, Old Fred!
嘿 弗瑞德
Hey, Fred!
弗瑞德
Fred? Fred?
- 奇怪了 - 真是奇怪
- This is weird. - This is real weird.
- 天啊 - 到底怎么回事？
- Jesus! - What the hell's going on?
到底发生什么事？
I mean, what the hell is going on?
大家快离开这里 附近有个杀人狂
Get the hell out of here! There's a killer on the loose!
- 什么？ - 凶手 一个真正的疯子
- What? - A murderer, man! A real psycho!
他把人头切下来 我不是开玩笑的
He's cutting people's heads off. I'm not kidding!
他们在耍我们
They're pulling our chain.
对
Yeah.
搞什么？
What?
可恶
Shit.
霍尔 霍尔
Howard!
卡麦？
Carmine?
是谁干的？
Who could be doing it?
我不是在指控任何人
I'm not accusing anybody,
只是告诉你 我的一些牛不见了
but saying some of my cattle are missing.
你说真的？老弗死了？
Are you serious? Old Fred's dead?
差不多
Something like that.
你在鬼扯 对吧？
You're bullshitting me.
- 弗瑞德怎么了？ - 比艾格更惨
- What happened to Fred? - Worse than Edgar.
- 弗瑞德怎么了？ - 你们不会相信的
- What happened to him? - You won't believe it.
我要买条糖果
I need a candy bar.
真不敢相信 电话坏了
I don't believe this. The phone's dead.
- 华特 你的电话坏了 - 我没动它
- Walter, your phone is dead! - I didn't do it.
纳斯特 怎么回事？
Nestor, what's happening?
有人杀了老弗
Somebody killed old Fred.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
小瓦 你们得去毕斯比找警察来
Val, you've got to get to Bixby, and get the police up here
动作快点
.And step on it.
我们马上出发
Consider it stepped on.
（离开完美山谷）
我们就差晚了一天决定离开这鬼地方
We decided to leave this place one damn day too late, you know?
现在没有任何事能阻止我们
There's sure as hell nothing to stop us now.
从这里到毕斯比的路上 我们认识的人全都死了
Everybody we know between here and Bixby is already dead.
小心
Look out!
是不是老天爷在惩罚我们？
Is there some higher force at work here?
我们对人生有要求过多吗？
I mean, are we asking too much of life?
这些家伙跑哪去了？
Where the hell are these guys?
他们在做什么？爆破吗？
What are they doing? Blasting?
嘿
Hey!
你们在哪？这哪像在修路啊 混蛋
Where are you guys? It's not like there's another road, assholes!
小瓦 小瓦
Val? Val!
- 老天 真不敢相信 - 你让车卡住了
- Jesus! I don't believe this! - You're hung up.
我没有
I am not!
我告诉你 车卡住了
You're hung up, I tell you!
你会把离合器烧坏
You're going to burn the clutch!
那样开会把车辆给弄断
You could break an axle like that.
你能不能闭嘴？
Could you shut up?
我可不要在这里过夜
I don't need to spend the night out here.
爱哭鬼
Crybaby.
- 会是土狼吗？ - 不可能
- Could it have been coyotes? - No way.
土狼不会切了弗瑞德的头
Coyotes didn't kill Fred.
嘿 小瓦和厄尔来了
It's Val and Earl.
他们不应该在这里
They shouldn't be here already.
- 我以为你们到毕斯比了 - 你们绝不会相信的
- Thought you two were in Bixby by now. - You're won't believe this.
- 妈 - 哦 我的天
- Mom! - Oh, my God!
- 柏特 小心点 - 不会吧
- Burt, be careful. - Unreal.
- 你们从哪弄来的？ - 我并不知道它在车底下
- Where'd you get it? - I didn't know we had it.
- 真恶心 - 是蛇吗？
- It's disgusting. - Some kind of snake?
我看更像只鳗鱼
It's more like an eel to me.
鳗鱼住在水里 不是吗？
Eels live in the water, don't they?
- 或许是蛞蝓妈妈 - 别碰
- Big mother slug, maybe. - Don't touch!
放心 它死了
Relax. It's dead.
那时一定是被它抓住 所以车子才动不了
It must've grabbed us! That's why the truck stalled.
下次我说我没卡住
I said I wasn't hung up.
等等 这东西让你们的车动不了
This stalled out your truck?
它一定是个力气很大的畜牲
It'd have to be one strong son of a bitch.
而且也很臭
Stinks, too.
我用5元跟你买
I'll give you boys $5 for this.
20元
$20.
- 好吧 10元 - 15元
- Okay, $10! - $15.
- 好 15元 - 没错 15元
- Okay, $15. - Damn right, $15.
我不相信你们
I don't believe you guys.
可能是条蛇
Could be a snake!
发生突变的蛇
Some kind of mutation.
没错
Yeah.
不管它是什么
Whatever it is…
单单一只没法吃掉弗瑞德 以及全部的羊群
just one of these couldn't eat up Fred and his whole flock of sheep.
所以你认为那里还有更多只？
You think there are more out there?
累死我了 这些留着明天早上再弄
I'm dead. Let's put this stuff up in the morning.
不行
Uh-uh.
我们明早要去毕斯比
We have to go to Bixby in the morning.
- 煤渣砖送来了 - 哦 煤渣砖
- The cinder blocks are in. - The cinder blocks.
哦 我的天
Oh, my God!
看看这美丽的天空
Just keep looking at that beautiful sky.
等房子盖好后 这片天空将天天照耀着我们的屋顶
That's the sky that'll be over our roof every night when we're done.
如果不盖屋顶呢？
What if we don't finish the roof?
那么就能一直享受这片天空 对吧？
Then we can look at the sky all the time.
哦 又是那鬼东西
That damn thing.
或许我们该买个新的发电机吧？
Maybe it's time we buy a new generator.
它不见了
It's gone!
什么叫它不见了？
What do you mean, it's gone?
你确定它本来在这儿吗？
You sure this is where it was?
是这里没错 这里有电线
It was right here! There's the cord.
拿着
Hold this.
可能陷进去了 这附近有很多矿坑
Maybe the ground caved in. There's mines and stuff around here.
那就别拉了 你不想掉进去吧
Well, don't then. You don't want to fall in.
咱们走
Let's go.
天啊 什么东西那么臭？
God, what is that stink?
你听到了吗？
You hear that?
快点 快点 咱们走
Come on. Let's just go.
我们快回镇上 拜托 吉姆
Let's go back to town or something. Please, Jim!
可能是地质之类的关系 比如天然气或喷泉
Maybe it's a geological thing like natural gas…
都有这种臭味
or a geyser. They stink like that.
记得黄石公园吗？
Remember in Yellowstone?
有东西抓住我
Something's got me!
不 吉姆 不
No, Jim, no!
有东西把我往下拉
Something's got me down here!
哦 吉姆
Oh, Jim!
哦 天啊 哦 天啊
Oh, God, oh!
快找东西来 把我拉上去
Get something. Get me out of here!
吉姆
Oh, oh! Jim!
有东西抓住我 哦 天啊 拜托救我出去
Something's got me. Please get me out!
救救我
Help me!
吉姆
Jim!
哦 我的天
Oh, my God.
（与蛇合照 只要3元）
敏蒂 笑一个
Mindy, smile. Honey,
快点 亲爱的 别那么害怕 它不会伤害你的 我保证
Don't look so afraid. It won't hurt you. I promise
- 敏蒂 看这里 笑一下 - 快点
- Mindy look up. Smile. - must
别动
Hold it.
马文 滚开
Melvin, get out of there!
- 老张真是机灵 我没说错吧 - 只卖可恶的15元
- Old Chang, slick as snot, and I ain't lying. - A lousy $15.
一个会事先规划的人
A man who plans ahead.
听着 我们要自我防卫 设立阵线 轮流守卫
We arm ourselves, we set perimeters, we stand guard.
只要那些蛇出现 我们就把它们灭绝
Any of those snake things show up here, we make them extinct.
- 太好了 - 拜托 柏特 你太紧张了
- All right! - Burt, get serious.
是啊 你搞得像在打仗一样
Yeah! You make it sound like a war.
你们这些人干嘛排斥事先防御？
What've you got against being prepared?
- 糖在哪？ - 又一个蓝波
- Where is the sugar? - Rambo.
等等 华特有无线通讯
Walter's got a CB radio.
何不和毕斯比市联络？找警察来
Why aren't you calling Bixby? The police…
不行 因为那些山 无线讯号出不了山谷
no We can't reach outside the valley because of the mountains.
马文 你是下一个 快坐下 假装很害怕的样子
You're next. Sit down, look scared.
好的
Yeah
电话坏了 路也断了 只能靠自己
The phone's out. The road's out. We're on our own.
你们俩最喜欢这样 不是吗？
You two are just loving it, aren't you?
拜托 南茜 别针对个人
Nancy, don't get personal about this!
- 我们得做些准备 - 对 没错
- We've got to do something. - Hell, yes!
我们完全被隔绝了
We are completely cut off.
北边是峭壁 东西面是高山
We got the cliffs to the north, mountains to the east and the west.
那就是海瑟和我在这里定居的原因
That's why Heather and me settled here.
地形上完全孤立
Geographic isolation.
一定还有别的求救方式
There's got to be a way we can get help.
这里可不是月球
This isn't the moon!
你想怎么做 走60公里的路到毕斯比求救？
What are you going to do, walk the 38 miles to Bixby?
华特有鞍马
There's Walter's saddle horses.
要拍了 随你们使用
That's it. You're welcome to them.
得有人骑去毕斯比市
Somebody could ride to Bixby.
很好 很好
That's not bad.
谁最会骑马？
Who's best on a horse?
华特 它们最好能跑得很快
They better be fast.
我们可不想被那些怪兽困住
We don't want to be stuck on a couple of canners.
那些蛇怪速度没那么快
Those snakes couldn't travel that fast.
你知道个屁 它们可能还会飞呢
For all you know they could fly.
你要哪一个？手枪还是艾格的来福枪？
What do you want? This Colt or Edgar's old rifle?
来福枪
Rifle.
厄尔 追里有一些乳酪和子弹
Here's some Swiss cheese and bullets.
谢了 华特
Thanks.
- 准备好了吗？ - 准备好了
- You guys all set? - Ready as we'll ever be.
海瑟和我开车逛逛
Heather and I drive around.
看是否能找到那个大学女孩 叫她回镇上来
We're going to find that college girl, tell her to get her ass back into town.
好主意 我们会顺路去找医生 看他们是否去了毕斯比
Good idea. We'll stop by the doctor's place and see if they went into Bixby.
等一下
Wait a minute, guys.
你们得带火力更强的武器
Take something that packs more of a punch than that.30-30
何不带我们的自动步枪？
Why don't you take one of our Browning autos?
或是更好的 我的70型自动枪？
Or better than that. Take my Model 70?
这是点375自动连发枪
It's.375 "H and H" mag.
谢了 海瑟
Thanks, Heather.
希望不会用到它
I hope we don't need to use it.
它抓住我了
It's got me! It's got me!
成熟点
Grow up!
可恶 马文
Damn it!
- 他只是开玩笑 - 你差点就没命
- He's only kidding. - You came that close.
差一点点
Too close.
别再开玩笑
No more games.
马文 你总有一天会被痛扁一顿
One of these days somebody's going to kick your ass.
医生？
Doctor?
老天 我真恨那鬼东西
I hate this shit.
等等
Wait a minute.
车子不在 我们只是错过他们而已
The car's gone. We just missed them, that's all.
那首老歌从哪传出来的？
Where's the goddamn golden oldie coming from?
- 这是什么鬼东西？ - 我不知道
- What the hell's this? - You got me.
好了 计划是这样 我们连停都不停 快速地跑
Here's the plan. We don't even stop. We ride like hell.
晚上也不休息 牵着马走
Tonight we'll keep right on going. We'll walk the horses.
那就是计划
That is the plan.
该死 究竟是什么鬼东西
What the hell are those things?
能把整部车埋起来？
How could they bury a station wagon?
它们为何这么做？
Why would they do it?
快点 小子 快点 走
Come on, git!
华特不知道一匹好马 在它不听话时就要扁它屁股
Walter wouldn't know a decent horse if it bit him in the ass.
等等 它们可能感受到一些不安的事
Wait a minute. They got wind of something they don't like.
走啊
Git.
这里不太对劲
Something's going on.
我什么也没看到
I don't see anything anywhere!
- 嘿 嘿 你还好吗？ - 我的马呢？
- Are you okay? - Yeah. What about my horse?
什么东西
What in the name of…
原来它们躲在地底下 窜出来抓你
That's how they get you. They're under the goddamn ground.
- 它们到底是什么东西？ - 狗娘养的畜牲
- What the hell are they? - Sons of bitches!
一定有很多只
Must be a million of them!
没有 只有一只
Nope. Just one.
快点
Come on.
它在追我们
He's gaining on us!
你看
Look!
我们一定办得到
We can make it!
笨蛋畜牲
Stupid son of a bitch.
它把自己撞昏
It knocked itself cold.
不是撞昏
Cold, my ass!
是撞死
He's dead.
我们杀了它
We killed it.
We killed it!
操你的
Fuck you!
嘿 各位 怎么回事？
Hey, guys. What's going on?
你们一分钟前 有没有发现什么奇怪的事？
Did you notice anything weird a minute ago?
刚刚
I mean, it just happened…
那是什么？
What's that?
好了 数到三 一起用力
All right, together. One, two, three.
我的天啊
Jesus Christ!
是不是死了才那么臭？
Does it smell like that because it's dead?
我没看到眼睛
I don't see any eyes.
一定是生存在地底下
Must be totally subterranean.
那些是触角
And those tentacles.
它们把触角从嘴里射出来
You know, I think they shoot right out of its mouth…
钩住你 然后再拉回嘴里
and they hook you and pull you right in.
幸好我们在它杀更多人之前 制止了它
Good thing we stopped it before it killed anybody else.
这很重要
This is important, you know.
这像是
This is like…
就这么说吧
well, let's just say it.
它可能是这世纪以来 动物学上最大的发现
This is probably the biggest zoological discovery of the century.
嘿 看看这个
hey. Check this out.
我找到这混蛋的尾巴
I found the ass end.
老天 我们真的抓到大怪物
Jesus, we really caught something here.
- 哇 - 天啊
- Wow! - Man!
那可真大
That's one big mother.
一定就是这老怪物 让你的地震仪不停地工作
This must be the old boy had your seismos working overtime.
对
Yeah.
它一定是利用这些东西来行动
It must push itself along with these.
当全部一起动时
All of them pushing at once.
它就能移动得这么快
That's why it moved so fast.
这玩意全身都是感应器 不
I mean This thing had sensors tripping all over the place. No…
兰达 你听说过像这样的玩意吗？
Rhonda, you ever heard of anything like this before?
当然 厄尔 大家都听过
Oh sure. Everybody knows about them.
只是没人告诉你
We just didn't tell you.
胡扯 没人见过这种怪物
Hell, man, no one ever saw anything like this!
我们挖到一些宝了
We're really onto something.
我告诉你吧
I'll tell you,
老张别想再用15元买下它
old Chang don't get his slick mitts on this for no measly $15.
你说得对
You got that right.
很好 计划是这样的 我们需要一个拖板车
All right, here's the plan. We need a flatbed…
- 对 还要一个绞盘 - 大约能举起4 5公吨重
- Right, with a winch. - A five- ton maybe.
不行 不能用绞盘 它会把它撕裂
No, don't want a winch. It'd tear it all up.
- 好吧 起重机呢？ - 对 起重机有吊带
- A crane? - Yeah, a crane with lifting straps.
嘿 安静
Hey. Shut up.
我算了算 这附近还有三只
There are three more of these things.
什么？
What?
还有三只？
Three more?
我在整个山谷放了地震仪 如果把不同的读数做个比较
I've got seismographs all over the valley. Compare the readings.
昨天下午两点这里有一只
Here's one at 2:00 yesterday.
但是同个时间近5公里处还有一只 这样就是两只了
But here's one three miles away at the exact time. That's two.
- 但这里 - 对 我们相信你
- But here… - We'll take your word.
- 你的卡车呢？ - 在山坡后面
- Yeah, where's your truck? - Just beyond that hill.
怎么了？
What?
- 臭土拨鼠挖的洞 - 小畜牲
- Damn prairie dog burrow. - Little sons of bitches.
走这边
This way!
到石头上去
Up on that rock!
看来就是它抓住我们的卡车
Looks like the one that got our truck.
- 你的车到底在哪？ - 就在那里
- Where the hell's your truck? - Right over there.
天啊 我想我们过不去了
I don't think we can make that.
至少它不会爬
At least he can't climb.
哦 天啊
Whew. Oh, man!
活的比死的还臭
Live ones smell worse than the dead ones.
我知道了
I got it.
它们一定是辐射造成突变
They're mutations caused by radiation.
不 不
Or no.
是政府制造出来 要送给俄国人的一个大惊喜
The government built them. Big surprise for the Russians.
我确定在化石纪录里 没有和它们类似的东西
There's nothing like them in the fossil record. I'm sure.
所以它们是在化石纪录前就有的生物
Okay, so, they predate the fossil record.
也就是说它们几十亿年前就存在
That would make them a couple billion years old.
而我们直到今天才看到
And we've just never seen one untill now.
对吧
Right.
我认为是外星物种 不可能是地球土生土长的
I vote for outer space. No way these are local boys.
已经好几小时没动静了
Well, haven't seen a sign for hours.
- 一定跑远了 - 对 一定是的
- Must be long gone. - Yeah, must be.
你下去走走不就知道了吗？
Why don't you take a little stroll and find out?
我们得试试
We've got to do something.
「我们得试试」
"We've got to do something."
真不懂为什么每次「我们」 最后都变成「我」
I don't know why "we" always has to be "me" every damn time.
我长得像什么？虫虫专家吗？
We, we, we. What do I look like? An expert on worms?
小心 小瓦 两公尺内它都钩得到
Watch it, it's got a good six-foot reach.
谢了 厄尔
Thank you, Earl.
畜牲
Son of a bitch!
该死得畜牲
Son of a goddamn bitch!
抱歉说粗话
Pardon my French.
可恶 它一直在这里等？
Shit! It's been waiting here all this time?
它怎么知道我们还在这儿？
How's it know we're still here?
它没眼睛吧？在地底下也闻不到我们
It's got no eyes, right? Sure as hell can't smell us underground.
我敢说一定是用听的
It's been listening.
当然
Of course!
它能感受到地面的震动
It senses seismic vibration.
尤其是在这石头上
It can hear every move
我们一举一动它都听得到 因为石头是个导体
we make on this rock. It's a perfect conductor!
意思是我们被困住了 我快疯了
That means we're stuck. That pisses me off!
我讨厌没教养 但我得方便一下
I hate to be crude, but I've got to take care of business.
- 我也是 - 我也是
- Me, too. - Same here.
谢了
Thanks.
不客气
No problem. Anytime.
有什么计划？
Well, what's the plan?
首先我们得看看 那老家伙还在不在
The first thing we've got to do is see if old Stumpy's still out there.
- 铲子借一下？ - 好
- Can I borrow that shovel? - Yeah.
难道它无家可归？
Doesn't he have a home to go to?
所以艾格才不肯离开电塔
That's why Edgar never got down off that damn tower.
我想我有个主意
I have an idea.
我们得想些办法 不然就得等死
You know, we have to come up with a plan or he's going to wait us to death.
- 我在想 - 何不跑跑看？
- I was thinking… - Why not run?
我们昨天就跑赢了
We outran him yesterday.
跑？跑并不是计划
Run for it? Running's not a plan.
跑是计划失败后的下下策
Running's what you do when a plan fails.
小瓦 你根本没动脑想计划
You're not trying to think of a plan.
但我们并没有多少选择
It ain't like we got a hell of a lot of options.
永逮都有选择 只要努力地想
There's always options. We've just got to think of them.
好吧 你就开始想吧
Why don't you start thinking?
为何一直都是我在伤脑筋？
Why do I always have to do all the thinking?
- 让你成为爱因斯坦啊 - 你们会撑竿跳吗？
- Who died and made you Einstein? - You know how to pole vault?
只要跳到它抓不到的地方
We just stay where he can't get us…
跳到这些大石头上
on these residual boulders.
我的车就停在另一边
My truck's parked next to one.
一定要跳到石头上
Stay on those residual boulders!
那个谭米琳芭丝特会撑竿跳吗？
That Tammy Lynn Baxter, she do much pole vaulting?
可恶
Shit!
真不赖
That's pretty good.
一旦跳到卡车 那家伙不会给我们太多时间
That slimebag won't give us much time once we hit that truck.
- 我们得一起跳 - 没错
- I say we all jump together. - Right.
等等
Wait.
好了 准备
Okay, ready.
一 二 三
One, two, three!
快走 快走 快走
Go!
小心 小瓦
Watch it, Val!
快走 快走
Move!
谁来帮我一下吧？
Can somebody, perhaps, help me?
不 不
No!
像蛇一样的东西只是它的舌头之类的
The snake things are just their tongues.
这些怪物很庞大
These animals are huge!
抱歉 我觉得很不安
I'm sorry. I'm having a real difficult time with this.
拜托 你们快回答
Come on, you guys, answer.
- 快回来 - 嘿 华特
- Come on, you - guys,
- 柏特和海瑟去哪了？ - 我连络不上他们
- Where's Burt and Heather? - I can't reach them.
我猜他们还开着车到处看看
I guess they're still driving around somewhere.
嘿 兰达 那些东西叫什么？
What's the name you call those things?
它们从哪来？
Where do they come from?
- 我不知道 - 你是个科学家 不是吗？
- I don't know. - You're a scientist, aren't you?
应该有套理论之类的吧？
Aren't you supposed to have a theory?
听着 这些生物从没被发现过
These creatures are absolutely unprecedented.
对 但它们从哪来的？
yeah. But where do they come from?
对啊
Yeah!
它们从哪来的并不重要
It doesn't matter where they come from.
没有名字吗？
No name.
我们发现的 就该替它命名
We discovered them, we should name them!
华特 别想什么命名
Forget the damn name!
我和厄尔认为最好离开山谷去求援
Now me and Earl need to get out of this valley.
慢点 小瓦 先别冲动
Hang on. Let's not go off half-cocked.
是啊 一旦有人发现路不通
Somebody's bound to come check on us once they see the road is out…
- 电话也不通时 就会派人来找我们 - 对 说得没错
- and the lines are down. - That's how it works.
- 还是「舌怪」「舌蟒」 - 我喜欢蛇蟒
- "Suckoids." - "Oids." I like "snakeoids."
只要一靠近 我就用2公斤多的锄头敲死它
One of them comes near me and I'll hit him with a five-pound pickax.
你不了解 纳斯特
You don't understand.
它们是从地底下窜出来偷袭你
They come up from the ground and grab you.
它们能感应到地面的震动
They sense the slightest vibration through the ground.
就连脚步声也能感应 它们就是追样猎食的
Even footsteps. That's how they hunt.
所以我们就不能动 对吧？
So we don't vibrate, right?
或许它们根本不会来这里
Maybe they won't even come through here.
或许也不会骚扰我们
Maybe they'll leave us alone!
我要用电锯
Chain saw. That's what I'll use.
嘿 嘿 嘿 醒醒吧
hey. hey. hey, Wake up!
看好
Now, look!
它们正朝着我们来
They're headed right for us!
它们把艾格困在这里 老弗则死在这里
They trapped Edgar here. Grabbed old Fred right here.
在路上吃了那两个可怜的工人 而医生则死在这里
Nailed those two poor suckers on the road and the doctor's place is here!
现在这整个山谷都是它的点心
This valley is just one long smorgasbord.
我们得离开这里
We have got to get out.
我得去找敏蒂
I'm going to get Mindy.
哦 她没事 我看到她在街上玩
She's okay. I saw her playing down the street.
我喜欢「霸王蟒」 就用这名字
That's what I like, "Graboids"! That's it, "graboids"!
天啊 华特
Jesus, Walter.
若不替它命名 我们一定会很遗憾
We're going to be sorry if we don't give it a name.
好吧 小瓦 你要我们离开这里
Okay, you say let's get out of here.
那么我们该去哪里？
Where are we supposed to go?
兰达有个主意
Rhonda's got an idea about that.
它们在新生代冲积岩来去自如
See, they move very easily through the Pleistocene alluvials.
也就是泥土
The dirt.
整个山谷都由松软的泥土覆盖而成
The loose soil that covers the valley floor.
但它们无法穿过岩石区
But they can't move through rock.
所以我认为应该朝西走向山区
We should go west to the mountains.
她是指旧得吉普车道
She means up the old Jeep trail.
如果整座山都是坚硬的花岗岩 我们就安全了
If those mountains are granite we'd be safe.
可以一路走到毕斯比 如果
We could hike along them to Bixby if we…
我吓到你了 对不对？
I scared you, didn't I?
你这小混蛋
You little ass wipe.
你若不住手 就和这颗他妈的球一起滚
You don't knock it off, you're going to be shitting this basketball.
抱歉又说粗话
Pardon my French.
敏蒂
Mindy
和纳斯特一起 就得多花好几天才能找到救兵
It's going to take us days to get back with help with Nestor.
我们不会抛下你的
We're not going to leave you alone.
- 可恶 我要踢烂他的屁股 - 我去帮你
- Damn it! I'm going to kick his ass! - I'm going to help you.
马文
Melvin!
那个小混帐呢？
Where is that little shit stain?
马文 给我
Melvin, get your…
进去 进去
Get inside!
- 快跑 快点 - 快点 进去
- Run! Come on! - Come on, get in!
- 老天 华特 你有枪吗？ - 没有
- Walter, you got a gun? - No!
- 我们该怎么办？ - 安静 安静
- What are we going to do? - Be quiet!
它在哪？
Where is he?
现在记住 别出声 别动
Now remember, no noise, no vibrations.
哦 不 敏蒂
No, Mindy.
停下来
Stop.
敏蒂 下来 别玩弹簧高跷
Mindy, get off the pogo stick.
敏蒂
Mindy
- 小瓦 去叫她 - 敏蒂 回来
- Get her, Val! - Mindy, come back!
敏蒂
Mindy
- 敏蒂 - 安静 安静 别动
- Be quiet. - Don't move.
敏蒂 退后 退后
Mindy, get back.
跑 进屋里去
Run! Get in the house!
我们得去救他 它会把整部车拉下去
Get him off or it'll suck that truck down.
看在老天份上 快回去
Go back, for Chrissake!
天啊 又来一只
Jesus, here comes another one!
跑 快点 快点
Run! Come on!
把裤子脱掉
Get out of your pants!
小心
Look out!
快跑
Run!
跑 别回头 快点 快点
Don't look back. Come on!
抱歉
Sorry.
- 兰达 这些给你 - 谢谢
- Rhonda, here. - Thank you.
现在该怎么办？它们多久才会离开？
What are we going to do? How long untill they go away?
它们很有耐心
They got the patience of Job.
会一直等下去 直到听到像是午餐的东西出现
They sit and wait until they hear something that sounds like lunch.
- 我们得想个计划 - 我有个计划
- We've got to have a plan. - I got a plan.
你和小瓦开车到山里
You drive the truck up to the mountain,
走到毕斯比求援
walk to Bixby, get some help.
华特 那些怪物吃了我们的卡车
Those scumsuckers ate our radials.
你可以开我的车
You can take my truck.
不行 我们需要四轮传动的车 才能爬吉普车道
No, we need a major four-wheel drive just to get up that Jeep trail.
那条路崎岖不平
That trail's all messed up.
关掉
Turn it off!
拉开 拉开
Pull it back!
拔掉了
I got it.
手伸过来 手伸过来
Give me your hand!
畜牲
Son of a bitch.
Son of a bitch!
快 快走 到屋顶去
Come on, let's go! The roof!
快点
Come on!
- 跳 蔺达 你办得到 - 不 我不行
- Jump! You can do it! - I can't!
兰达 别停 继续跑
Don't stop. Keep moving!
哦 我的天
Oh, my God.
嘿
Hey!
你还好吗？
You okay?
嘿 怎么回事？你们在吗？
What's going on? Where are you guys?
怎么啦？你们在上面干嘛？
What's up? What the hell are you doing up there?
马文 闭嘴
Shut the hell up.
- 爬到屋顶上 - 不行
- Get up on your roof. - No way!
纳斯特？
Nestor.
南茜 到屋顶上
Nancy, get up on your roofs.
到屋顶上 它们会从地板窜出来
Up on your roofs! They come through the floor.
（乌兹冲锋枪保护你）
我不明白也不相信
I don't know. I can't believe it.
不见踪影
No tracks.
没有征兆 没有踪迹
No sign. No spoor.
可能吃了那么多羊 得去某个地方拉肚子
You'd think after eating all those sheep they'd have to take a dump someplace.
对 我也搞不懂
Yeah. I don't understand it.
华特 我是柏特 请回答
Walter, this is Burt. Come back.
华特？有人在吗？
Walter? Anybody copy?
请回答
I'm waiting.
- 华特 你在吗？请回答 - 好了 我拿到了
- Walter, you there? Come back! - Okay, I got it.
看在上帝的份上 是谁在看店啊？
Who's minding the store, for God's sake?
听着 柏特 我们知道是什么东西杀了大家
Burt, listen. We found out what's been killing people.
- 要说「完毕」 - 完毕
- Say "over." - Over.
收不到 华特 检查一下频率
Negative copy on that, Walter. Check your frequency.
我在22号频道 请回答
I'm on 22. Come back.
柏特 听得到吗？完毕
Burt, can you hear me now? Over.
小瓦 是你吗？怎么回来了？
Is that you? What're you doing back already?
柏特 那边一定出了什么怪事
Something real weird's going on over there.
他们全站在屋顶上
They're up on top of the roof.
我想它们要去找柏特
I think they're going for Burt's.
天啊 它们真的去了
Man! They're going!
柏特 快离开地下室 带着无线电
Burt, get out of your basement. Take your radio.
快和海瑟爬到屋顶上去 待会再谈好吗？完毕
You and Heather get up on your roof. We'll talk later. Over.
屋顶？小瓦 你在说什么？
Up on the roof? What are you talking about?
可恶 柏特 就听他的 事情不太对劲
Damn it, Burt. Listen to him. Something's wrong.
柏特 老天
Burt, Jesus Christ!
快爬到屋顶上去 怪物来了
Get up on your roof! The things!
它们在地底下
They're under the ground.
体型比我们想像的还大
They're bigger than we thought.
它们正朝着你们去了 马上就会到了
They're huge. They're coming after you. They're coming right now!
我们什么也没看到 小瓦 你到底在说什么？完毕
We don't see anything. What the hell are you talking about? Over.
柏特 它们在地底下
They're under the ground!
它们很会挖土 超大的怪物 在地底下行动 快走
They can dig. Big monsters! Underground! Now get out!
快
Hurry!
老天
Jesus…
柏特 快点
Burt, come on.
弹盒
Magazine!
在这里
Here!
找错对象了吧 你这混蛋
Broke into the wrong goddamn rec room, didn't you, you bastard?
我们杀了它 听到了吗？我们杀了那只大肉球 请回答
We killed it! You got that? We killed that motherhumper! Come back.
收到了 柏特 恭喜
Roger that, Burt. And congratulations.
但还有两只 重复一次 还有两只大肉球
Be advised, however, there are two more. Repeat, two more motherhumpers.
柏特杀了一只 解决了一只
Burt got one! He killed one!
- 太好了 - 很好
- Way to go, dude! - All right!
太好了 太好了
Yes! Yes!
再也不能嘲笑柏特的生活方式
I guess we don't get to make fun of Burt's lifestyle anymore.
柏特？
Say, Burt?
你有办法再干掉另外两条吗？请回答
Any chance you can get the other two? Come back.
等一下 老弟
One second, pal.
就算是猎枪也射不穿
You didn't get penetration even with the elephant gun.
可恶
Shit!
老天
Good Lord!
小瓦 我们没办法杀它
We can't get them.
从没想到还得先射穿泥土
I never figured on having to shoot through dirt.
就算用最好的枪也射不穿泥土 请回答
The best goddamn bullet stop there is. Come back.
让我跟他说话
Let me see that.
听着 柏特 别再射它们了 告诉我 你能回到车上吗？
Forget shooting them. Can you get to your truck?
- 完毕 - 没问题
- Over. - No problem.
很好 只有你的车
You have the only truck
能开上吉普车道
that can get up that Jeep trail.
现在听好 这是我的计划
Now listen. Here's the plan.
你和海瑟去求救 往山上开 再一直走
You and Heather go for help. You get to the mountains and…
各位 各位
You guys!
- 过来 - 等一下
- Come over. - Hang on a sec.
- 又有动静了 - 它好像不是原来那只肥仔
- He's up to something. - If it isn't our old pal Stumpy.
畜牲
Bastard.
兰达 你想它在干嘛？
What do you think it's trying to do?
你干嘛老是问我？
Why do you keep asking me?
- 搞什么 - 搞什么
- What the - What the
到底在搞什么？
What the hell was that?
呼叫厄尔 你要我们怎么做？请回答
Breaker there, Earl. What did you want us to do? Come back.
等等 柏特 这畜牲在搞新花样
Hang on, Burt. This bastard's trying something new.
完毕
Over.
她们没有出声音
They wasn't making no noise.
为什么会去找她们？
Why is he bothering them?
看来好像它在研究房子 试着理出头绪
It's like it's studying the buildings, trying to figure them out.
它们感受得到我们产生的震动 却又找不到在哪
They can feel our vibrations but they can't find us.
在我看来 它们似乎在拟定计划
Looks to me like they're coming up with a plan.
小心 纳斯特
Watch it, Nestor!
老天
Jesus!
可恶 真是受够了
Shit! Enough!
- 别待在地上 纳斯特 快走 - 离开那里 离开地面
- Get off the ground! Get moving! - Get out of there!
快走 快走
Move it!
不行 纳斯特 快点 你得爬高一点
No, that's no good! You've got to get higher!
不 不 天啊
No way!
不 你们得想点办法
No! You guys have got to do something!
你们得想点办法
You've got to do something!
柏特 海瑟？
Burt? Heather?
是 听到了 小瓦 请回答 完毕
You got us. Come on back. Over.
我们这边情况不太好 得改变计划才行
We're in deep shit over here. We'll have to change that plan.
- 柏特 住手 - 我想我把它吓跑了
- Burt, cut it out! - I think I scared him.
去求救无济于事
No use going for help.
在你们回来前 我们早就挂了
We'd be dead long before you'd ever get back.
好吧 小瓦 就听你的 只要告诉我该怎么做 完毕
Ok Val We're with you. Tell us what you want to do.
在我们底下的这些家伙 会把整座城给拆了
This one's going to tear this town out from under us.
我们得一起离开这里
We're going to have to get out of here together…
- 现在 - 好的 小瓦
- now. - Okay.
我们会去接大家 留在那儿等 完毕
We're coming after everybody. Just hang tight. Over.
你看
Yo.
小瓦 你得放弃卡车计划了
You're going to have to forget about the truck.
我听到了 海瑟
Yeah, we've got you, Heather.
听着 情况仍然没变
Look. The situation hasn't changed.
我们还是得靠石头 一定有些办法的
We still have to make it to solid rock. There's got to be a way.
什么办法？我们没有任何工具到得了山区
Like what? There's nothing left that can make it to those mountains.
嘿 小瓦 安静
Quiet, man.
无所谓了 它们知道我们在这儿
It doesn't matter now. They know we're here.
可恶 我们需要的是直升机
We need a helicopter what we need. Or a goddamn tank!
- 或是坦克车 - 等等 等等 推土机
- Wait a minute. - The Cat!
- 我们可以用推土机吗？ - 老天 它比任何东西都慢
- Could we take the Cat? - Jesus. It's slower than hell.
对 但它至少有27公吨重 它们不可能举得起27公吨吧
But it weighs more than 30 tons. There's no way they could lift that.
- 能吗？我是说 - 但我们挤不下一台推土机
- Could they? I mean… - But we can't all fit on the bulldozer.
不
No.
不过后面可以拖东西
No, but we could…
拖一部车吧 我不知道
drag something, though. We could pull a car behind it. I don't know.
那辆旧得半拖车
Hell, that old semitrailer.
- 它的轮胎没气 - 不要紧
- Its tires are flat. - Doesn't matter.
- 推土机什么都能拖 - 没错
- That Cat can pull anything. - Well all right
- 只要能离开这里 - 我们有个计划了
- We just roll on out of here. - We've got a plan!
当然啦 还有一段长路得走
Of course, that's a hell of a long walk.
听着 它们只对震动有感应 对吧？
listen They only respond to vibration, right?
那么 何不分散它们的注意力？
Couldn't we distract them somehow?
对 好主意
yeah Good.
比如说用诱饵让它们忙碌
Something to keep them busy. Like a decoy.
马文 要不要赚点钱？
Melvin, you want to make a buck?
- 自己留着用吧 - 牵引机怎么样？
- Eat it! - How about tractor?
华特的小牵引机怎么样？把它发动
How about Walter's little tractor? Start him up.
再让它自己走
Let him go out by himself.
若那些东西喜欢噪音的话 就会跟着它到处走
Let those things follow him all over if they like that noise.
不赖哦 你觉得呢？
Not bad. What do you think?
愈来愈近了 厄尔
Ground's getting closer.
就照米奎尔的计划做吧
I say we go with Miguel's plan.
等等 南茜
Hold on, Nancy!
- 我去发动推土机 - 你别想
- I'm making the run for the Cat. - Like hell.
- 说真的 厄尔 我跑得比你快 - 但我开得比你好
- I'm faster than you. - But I'm best at driving the Cat.
- 我在时就不是 - 该死 听我说
- Not while I'm around. - Listen to me.
- 我比你老又比你聪明 - 对了一半
- I'm older and wiser - Well you're half right.
该死 我输了 我得去
Damn! I lost. Guess I'll have to do it.
我赢了 由我决定
I won. I pick who does it.
等你好了就走 米奎尔
Ready when you are, Miguel.
它在那里 它走了
There he is. There he goes!
它去追了 它去追了
He's chasing it!
它走了 这只也走了
It's going. This one's going, too!
- 祝你好运 猪头 - 别担心我 笨蛋
- Good luck, shithead. - Don't worry about me, jerk-off.
可恶
Shit!
你这自杀狂
You suicidal son of a bitch.
继续跑
Keep going!
哦 我的天 哦 我的天
Oh, my God. Oh my God
快点
Come on!
它们去追他了
They're going to get him!
小瓦 停下来 它们来了 安静
Val, stop! They're coming! Be quiet!
别动
Don't move!
很有效 它们找不到他
It worked. They can't find him.
我们得
We've got to…
我们得制造噪音
make some noise.
很多噪音
A lot of noise!
嘿 你这混蛋 回来抓我啊
You sorry sons of bitches. Come and get my ass!
在这里 黏答答的怪物 来抓我啊
Over here, you slime bucket! Come get me!
快点 你怕了吗？快点
What are you, scared? Come on.
嘿 她在做什么？
What's she doing?
太好了 好女孩 真是聪明
That did it, girl! Goddamn good thinking.
- 你还好吗？ - 还好
- You okay? - Yeah.
走吧
Here goes.
- 接着 - 好
- Here. - Yeah.
天啊
Goddamn!
装甲车
Armored transport.
柏特 海瑟
Burt, Heather!
我们走吧 快走
Let's get going!
柏特 海瑟
Burt, Heather!
你们俩快点 我们要到山区去
Come on, let's go, you two. We're headed for the mountains.
若是这样的话 我们得有所准备
If that's how we're doing it, we're going prepared.
我们撑不了多久的 那些家伙很聪明
We can't hold still long. These things are damn smart.
- 它们愈来愈聪明 - 没关系
- They're getting smarter by the minute. - Fine.
我们也有新玩意要来教训它们
We've got some new things to teach them.
看到没？
You see that?
它们又来了 每次我一停 它们就这样
They're doing it again. They try it every time we stop!
快下来
Come on!
老天 我们只要走14 15公里
Jesus Christ! We're only going nine miles.
那些家伙会跟着我们屁股走 对吧？
Those things will be on our ass every foot of the way, right?
- 快点 柏特 - 海瑟 你们到底在干嘛？
- Just hurry! - What are you doing up there?
- 没看到我们正往下沉吗？ - 快上车
- Can't you see we are sinking. - Get in the trailer!
你喜欢火力大的还是这个？
What do you think? Max firepower or this?
遣枝点458口径的 能射穿固体 也不用带太多弹药
I go for penetration. The.458, shooting solids. Less ammo to carry.
快点 柏特 快
Come on. Move it!
小心这些弹药盒
Watch these ammo boxes!
- 快点 柏特 - 快啊 海瑟
- Come on, Burt! - Heather, hurry!
- 叫他们快点 - 好了 下来
- Tell them to come on! - Okay, now!
下来 快点 快点
Now! Come on!
给我枪 我要干掉一只
Give me a gun. I'll take one.
就算是第三次世界大战 我也不会给你
I wouldn't give you a gun if it was World War III.
再见了 五年的存粮
Food for five years.
一千加仑的水 空气过滤器 净水器 盖氏计算器
1, 000 gallons of gas, air and water filtration, Geiger counter…
防空避难所
bomb shelter.
该死得地底怪物
Underground. Goddamn monsters!
快到了 坚硬的岩石区
There we go! Fallen Rock.
有它们得踪迹吗？
Any sign of them?
或许它们已经放弃了
Maybe they just gave up, you know?
那是什么？
What's that?
该死 它们在搞什么？
Damn it! What the hell are they doing?
只要不在这里捣乱 才不管它们搞什么
I don't care what they're doing as long as they're doing it way over there.
等一下 小心
Wait! Look out!
敏蒂
Mindy
- 妈咪 - 大家留在这里
- Mommy! Mommy! - Eveybody stay here.
- 柏特 你还好吗？ - 我没事
- Burt, you okay? - I'm okay.
它们要来抓我们吗？怎么回事？
Are they going to get us? What happened?
- 柏特 你真的没事？ - 没事
- Burt, you sure you're okay? - Yeah.
- 厄尔 怎么回事？ - 怎么回事？
- What happened? - What happened?
它们挖了一个陷阱
They dug a trap.
真令人难以置信
I can't believe this.
好
All right.
给你
Here.
给我一把枪
Let me have my gun.
饿了吗？吃这个吧
Hungry? Eat this!
大家趴下
Everybody down!
在那里
There they are!
- 杀掉了吗？ - 我不知道
- Did you kill one? - I don't know.
那里还有两只 有两个不同的泥土痕迹
No, there's still two of them.
- 肯定让它们不敢轻举妄动 - 三思
- There're two different dust trails. - Made them think twice.
那是什么玩意 柏特？
What's in those?
一些照比例混合的家用化学粉末
A few household chemicals in the proper proportion.
它们来了 它们回来了
Here they come. They're coming back!
我们得跑到那些石头上
We'll have to make a run for those rocks.
我不知道 小瓦 那太远了
I don't know. That's a long way.
会被抓到的
They'll get us!
若留在这里 一定会被抓到
They're going to get us if we stay here.
- 嘿 柏特 还有更多炸弹吗？ - 够你用的 兰达
- You have any more of those bombs? - We've got you covered.
如果朝我们要跑的方向丢
What if we throw one that way, the way we want to go?
那么它一爆炸 它们就会跑走
Then when it explodes I mean if it drives them away,
我们就他妈得拼命跑
we run like goddamn bastards.
抱歉说粗话
Pardon my French.
如果它们不怕 反而没跑呢？
What if they don't get scared? What if they don't run?
我认为它们会被吓跑的 炸弹伤过它们
I don't think it does scare them. It hurts them.
它们对声音很敏感 一定会跑开
They're sensitive to sound, they'll run.
我投她一票
Hell, she's got my vote!
好吧 我们就放手一搏吧
That's it! We're making a run for it!
- 朝石头那儿跑 - 我不知道 它们动作太快了
- We're going for the rocks. - I don't know. They're too fast.
- 绝不可能跑得过它们的 - 马文 这能吓走它们
- You can't out run them. No way! - This'll make them think twice.
大家准备好了吗？
Everybody ready to run?
趴下
Heads down!
成功了 它们走了
It worked! There they go!
好吧 咱们走
Let's go!
- 快 - 走吧
- All right - let's go!
快 柏特
Come on, Burt.
哦 柏特
Oh, Burt!
柏特 你这混蛋
Oh Burt You asshole!
妈咪
Agh! Mommy!
快起来
Get up.
- 快上来 - 我在你后面
- Get up here! - I'm with you, honey.
快 快 快
Go!
柏特 你这混蛋 枪里没子弹
You asshole! There are no bullets in this gun.
让你跑了 不是吗？
Got you moving, didn't it?
现在怎么办？
So now what?
可以用柏特的炸弹 一路跑到山区里吗？
Could we make it to the mountains? Use Burt's explosives?
不可能
No way.
那需要50颗才行
We'd need 50 of those bombs.
就这样了
That's it.
我们无法离开这石头了
We're not getting off this rock.
也不能用撑竿跳离开这里 这点绝对是的
We're not going to pole vault out of here. That's for damn sure.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你们在说什么？
What're you talking about?
好像已经放弃了一样
It's like you're giving up.
它们会等到我们挂了 那是它们的习惯
They'll wait out there untill we're dead. That's exactly what they do.
等一下
Wait!
看在上帝的份上 待在家里还有水 食物
For Chrissake, we could've made a stand at our place.
- 可以和它对抗 - 那样是没法和它们打的
- We had food, water… - You can't fight them like that.
那你们俩把我们拖来这里又能怎样？
So you two screw-ups hauled us way the hell out here?
你怎么不退一步想想 瘦竹竿？
Why don't you just back off, string bean?
我们真该把你留在屋顶不管
We could've left your ass on the roof!
真希望你做了 无能的领袖
I wish you had, fearless leader.
- 谁让你们俩当领导的？ - 别逼我
- Who put you two in charge? - Don't push me!
别他妈的逼我
Don't push me!
那只怪物不杀他 我也会杀了他
If them graboids don't kill him, I will.
什么？
What?
它们在半小时内 就会把你们的房子拆得粉碎
They'd have torn up your place in half an hour.
来吧 来吧 算了 别再想了
Come on. Just let it go. Forget about it.
我知道他自以为是
I know he does. He thinks he knows everything.
当快饿死时 我知道该怎么做
If it comes to starvation, I know what I'm doing.
拿着这个
Take one of these…
点燃它走出去 让它们把我吃了
walk right out there with the fuse lit and let them take me down.
砰
Boom.
老天 亲爱的
Good Lord, honey.
这点子还不赖
Now that's not a bad idea.
这让我想起一个方法
No. It gives me an idea.
就像钓鱼
Going fishing like.
正前方有一只
There's one. Straight out in front.
看看能不能让它留在那里
Let's see if we can keep him right there.
- 需要多久时间？ - 不知道 它们动作很快
- How much we need? - I don't know. They're pretty quick.
至少15秒
Fifteen seconds at least.
- 那是什么导火线？ - 大炮引线
- Which kind of fuse is that? - Cannon fuse.
- 你用它来做什么？ - 引爆大炮啊
- What the hell you use if for? - My cannon.
你们自己小心了
You guys watch yourselves.
在那里大约30
Right out there, about 30…
老天 你不会要表演套绳索吧？
You're not going do your lasso thing?
因为你不会套绳索
Just because you're no good with a rope.
好了 退后
All right, get back!
快点 宝贝
Come on, baby.
咬住它 咬住诱饵
Take it. Take the bait!
耶 太好了
Yeah! All right!
- 看看它 - 耶
- Look at it! - yeah
太好了
All right! Yeah!
很好 只剩一只了
Okay, one to go.
可恶 它在哪？
Damn! Where the hell is he?
希望它不是太聪明
Hope he didn't wise up.
在那里
There.
看看它
Look who it is.
那玩意给我
Give me that thing.
这只畜牲是我的了
This son of a bitch is mine.
好了
There it goes!
- 好 退后 - 知道了
- All right, get back! - I got it.
快来 快来
Come on.
快啊 午餐时间到了 猪头
Come on. Lunchtime, slophead.
好了 趴下
All right, get down!
可恶
Oh, shit!
哦 我的天 这是
Oh, my God! It's coming…
- 退回去 退回去 - 快跑
- Get back! - Run!
起来 快
Get up, come on!
你们在那儿干嘛？
What're you doing out there?
我们制造一些噪音 分散它的注意力 快点 各位
Okay, let's make some noise. Try to distract them.
鲜肉在这儿
Fresh meat!
等等
Wait.
这只竟然没上当
This one's not falling for it.
它不是个笨蛋
This one ain't dumb.
它想骗我们
He's trying to trick us.
用你的炸弹
Use your bomb.
这是最后一颗了
It's our last one.
你还能用在哪里？
What else you going use it for?
就算跑到石头区又能怎样？
So what if we make it to the rocks.
反正三天后也是死
We'll be dead in three days anyway.
那么 我想多活三天
I want to live for the three days.
怎么回事？
What the hell? What's the matter?
- 看在上帝份上 丢炸弹吧 - 丢炸弹 老兄
- Use the bomb, for God's sake! - Throw that bomb, man!
把它吓跑
Scare them away!
快丢炸弹
Throw the bomb!
这只畜牲不会比我们聪明
This bastard ain't smarter than us.
看在上帝份上 小瓦
For Chrissake, Val!
我要这么做
I'm going to go for it.
这么做？
Go for what?
- 你要干嘛？ - 我有个计划
- What are you doing? - I got a goddamn plan!
打火机呢？
Where the hell is it?
在我这里
I've got it!
这最好是个很棒的计划
This better be one hell of a great plan!
准备
Get ready!
- 点燃它 点燃它 - 还没到时候
- Light it, man! - Not yet.
快 你在等什么？
Come on. What are you waiting for?
现在
Go!
快点 快点 快点
Come on! Come on! Come on!
太远了 你丢到它后面去了
Too far! You threw it behind him.
小瓦 快跑
Run! Val
你会飞吗 笨蛋？你会飞吗？
Can you fly, you sucker?
我只是突然想到的
It just suddenly hit me, you know.
牛群狂奔
Stampede.
太棒了
Way to go, Val! Yeah!
太棒了 小瓦
我们一到毕斯比 就开始打电话
Now…the second we hit Bixby, we start making phone calls.
这件事能让我们赚点钱
We could make some real money on this thing.
还会登上People杂志
We could get in People magazine.
People杂志？是National Geographic杂志
People? Hell! National Geographic.
对 对 对
Yeah. Yeah.
笑一个
Smile.
柏特借我照相机
Burt loaned me his camera.
是哦 他也给了我们这些轮胎
Yeah. He gave us these tires, too.
真够刺激吧？
It's all pretty exciting, huh?
这里一定会成立一个研究小组 我会是其中一员
There's going to be research, and I'm going to be in on it.
首先要帮那只怪物多拍几张照片
The first thing to do is take pictures of that one we dug up.
对
Yeah.
照相是个好点子
Pictures seem like a good idea.
谢谢你所做的一切 救了我一命
Thanks for everything. Saving my life and stuff.
不客气
You're welcome.
或许将来会再见到你？
Maybe I'll see you sometime?
那么 再见了
well. See you.
我知道 我知道 我正要做
I know! I know. I'm working up to it.
我在做什么？
What am I doing?
像她这样的女人怎会看上我？
What's a woman like her want with a guy like me?
她会当她的博士
She's going for her damn Ph.D.
兰达？
Rhonda?
怎样？
Yeah?
我只是想
I just wanted to…